No! I'm not gonna go!
I hate seafood! It's gross!
I wanna have hamburgers.
Jason Michael Terwilliger,
you have five seconds.
One, two...
Yes. My name is Ellen Barrett.
I'm calling from Room
227 of the Sea View Motel.
I think I killed someone.
Uh-huh. Yes, I'll be here.
Ellen Barrett.
That's two R's and two T's?
Yes. I'm from Atlanta.
I'm a journalist. I write
a newspaper column.
And he is?
Was?
He said his name
was Adam Easley.
He worked for Vic Baron.
Vic Baron as in the mobster?
Easley called me
about a week ago
and said that he heard that I
was doing a story about his boss.
And that he and Baron
had had a falling out,
and he'd be more than
happy to rat on his boss.
I thought he was on the
level so I agreed to meet him.
And then when I got here...
What happened, Miss Barrett?
Well, it was a setup.
I'd no sooner shut the door
but he grabbed me and he
told me that Baron wanted me
to drop the story or else.
And then he started to throw
me around the room and he hit me,
until finally I...
Maybe we should do
this someplace else.
- Feeling better?
- Yeah.
- Okay. Do you mind if I turn this on?
- Go ahead.
Now, in as much detail
as you can remember,
tell me exactly what happened
in that motel room tonight.
Well, after I told Easley that I
wasn't about to drop the story,
and that he and Vic Baron
could pretty much shove it,
he grabbed me by the hair and
he threw me across the room.
I hit a chair on the way
down, and I knocked it over.
And then I got up pretty fast,
and I grabbed for the phone
to try to call for some help,
and he yanked the receiver out
of my hand and he hit me with it.
Hard.
Then what happened?
Well, then I scratched his face.
And I tried to run for the
door, but he pulled me back,
and he grabbed my blouse
and he started to slap me.
I thought he was gonna kill me,
so that's when I
saw the knife, and...
It was sitting on a tray
with a bunch of dirty dishes.
And I grabbed the
knife and I stabbed him.
How many times?
I have no idea.
According to measurements
taken by the coroner at the scene,
Mr. Easley was
about 6 feet tall.
How tall are you, Miss Barrett?
I'm 5'3".
Ben?
You here?
Go away.
You are here. Why didn't
you answer the door?
What are you reading?
Innocent Till Proven Dead.
I read that. Yeah,
it's pretty good.
Especially when you find
out who the murderer is.
I figured it was the DA.
I mean, who would have ever thought
it'd turn out to be the guy's own wife?
- Whoops.
- Billy, you just ruined it for me.
Well, heck, I didn't mean to.
Leanne sent this to me all
the way from Los Angeles.
I'm sorry.
How's she doing anyway?
Well, pretty good. Job
seems to be working out.
- She gonna stay?
- I imagine.
She met a fella.
Oh.
She didn't take your spark
plug wrench with her, did she?
- Spark plug wrench?
- Yeah, I need it.
That's why I came over.
Truck conked out on me again.
Did you ever consider getting
your own spark plug wrench?
Why?
We got yours.
- You know you got a message?
- Yeah, I'll get it later on.
Don't you wanna
know who it's from?
Ben, this is Ellen Barrett.
I'm in Wilmington, North
Carolina, at 910-555-7000.
Please call me as soon
as you get this message.
It's very important. Thanks.
Save that.
Who's Ellen Barrett?
A woman.
- A woman?
- Yeah.
I used to know her.
She was a reporter.
Covered the courthouse
for the Atlanta Herald.
Did you...?
No.
She was married.
She has her own syndicated
column, Pulitzer Prize winner,
and I just knew her.
Think you might be
going to Wilmington?
I don't know.
I got business there myself.
My truck's on the fritz. I
might go along with you.
Business...?
Eh...
It just so happens that
someone's interested
in buying the house
that Lucy left me.
Someone by the name
- of Clarence Litton.
- Clarence Litton?
Clarence Litton, the
billionaire with all the hotels.
What's Clarence Litton
want with that dump of yours?
I'll thank you not
to call it a dump.
The roof's bad,
the wiring's shot,
you need new plumbing,
it's termite-infested.
I've seen roaches.
- You have not.
- It's a dump.
It's a prime piece of
beachfront property
- that's gonna make me filthy rich.
- It's a dump.
Flight 584 to Charlotte
now boarding at Gate 5.
Mom.
Carrie.
Carrie, what are you doing here?
Dad and I are staying
at the beach house.
- Kind of a graduation present.
- Aw.
Your hair looks
pretty that way. I like it.
You look awful.
Oh, I didn't sleep, that's all.
How did you know I was here?
Well, Dad called your office
after he heard what happened.
Well, everything is okay.
Then why is Ben Matlock coming?
To make sure that
everything stays okay.
So just tell your father that...
Tell him everything is okay.
Why won't you let him help you?
Oh, Carrie, your father and I are
like oil and water. We don't exactly mix.
- He still cares about you.
- Carrie, don't involve yourself in this.
Tell him not to
worry. I can handle it.
Come on. Now, as long as
you're here, you can meet Ben.
Carrie!
Oh, Ellen.
- Oh, Ben.
- Hi.
- Good to see you.
- It's been a long time.
- Only about seven years.
Yeah. Long enough for you to
have acquired an entourage, I see.
Oh, no, no, we're
just traveling together.
This is Cliff Lewis.
An honor to meet you. I
read your column all the time.
And his father, Billy Lewis.
- Hello.
- Are you vacationing?
- Business.
I'm in real estate.
In fact, I'm in the process
of hammering out a deal
with Clarence Litton.
- Really?
- Yeah, Clarence contacted me
through the U.S. mail.
- He said, "Dear Mr. Lewis..."
- You don't wanna hear this.
Dad, Dad, Dad.
Just because you're
selling one lousy house,
does not give you the right to
tell people that you're in real estate.
- Does too.
- Does not.
Does too.
It's not a lousy house.
Hi. Peter Haskins.
- Come in.
- Oh, thanks.
Have a seat.
Where?
Oh, sorry.
You are Peter
Haskins, the deputy DA?
That's me.
You want me to
just hold that for you?
No. That's okay.
Okay.
You're here to discuss
- the Ellen Barrett case.
- That's right.
Barrett, Barrett...
Barrett...
Well, why haven't you
closed her case out?
Well, there are a
couple of inconsistencies
in the statement
she gave the police.
Inconsistencies?
Yes.
Yes. Uh...
Ones that tend to call
into question her claim
that she acted in self-defense.
I can give you specifics
just as soon as I find her file.
Is this it?
Ahem. Okay.
For instance, Adam
Easley, the fellow she killed,
she says he said he
worked for Vic Baron.
But so far, we haven't been
able to find any kind of connection
between this Easley
and Baron at all.
Well, if I were Vic Baron
and was gonna have
somebody roughed up,
I'd be sure whoever I sent to do
it couldn't be traced back to me.
Mm.
The second for instance,
she says Mr. Easley called her
at her home in Atlanta
last Friday night.
Right.
The thing about it is he was
staying at the Sea View Motel then,
and their records show he made
no call to her home that night
or any other night.
Maybe he called her
from somewhere else.
Their records do show that he
made other long distance calls
from his motel room.
It seems kind of strange he'd
leave just to make that one call.
Not if he didn't want
that one call to be traced.
Your point is well
taken, Mr. Matlock.
It could very well be
I'm nitpicking here.
But before I charge
somebody with a crime,
I always like to know for
sure just what that crime was.
Yeah.
You're not gonna lose
that file again, are you?
Oh, no, no. I'm
gonna put it right here.
Well, good.
Because the sooner you
can get this cleared up,
the sooner Ellen can
get on with her life.
- You keep in touch.
- Oh, yes. Thank you.
- Uh-huh. Well, I'll...
- No, no. No, sir.
- Let me get the door for you.
- Oh, okay.
Hon, I told you
not to go out there.
Well, I had to do something.
I mean, she's my mother.
I wanted her to know
that I'm worried about her,
that I care about her.
She just pushed
me away like always.
It's not you, Carrie. It's me.
I'm the one who she doesn't
want in her life anymore.
Which is okay, I understand.
No, it's not okay.
Because I don't understand.
Honey, you don't need to. This
is between your mother and me.
Dad, if I don't understand what
happened between you two,
how am I gonna know that the
same thing's not gonna happen to me?
How do I know that I'm not gonna
meet somebody and fall in love
and get married and have a kid,
only to wind up hating
my husband's guts?
Honey, she doesn't hate my guts.
Then what's the deal?
- Brad?
- Steve?
Yeah, Brad. What is the
holdup on the editorial?
Look, I don't give
a damn. Just run it.
You do not answer to him.
You answer to me, you got that?
And we're running
that piece tonight.
No. No, no, I wanna
see the whole page.
Just fax it here
as soon as it's set.
Well, that's why the paper's
paying you the big bucks, isn't it?
Well, Ben just called.
He talked to the DA,
and he should be here
in about 15 minutes.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- You sure I can't get you something?
- Oh, no, thanks. I'm fine.
You've got a nice
house here, Mr. Lewis.
Yes, I do, don't I? It's a
real nice house. Heh, heh.
Most people would pay a
fortune to own a place like this.
Yes, sir, a real fortune.
I'm a fair man, but when
something is of value, I...
Have you ever heard the
expression don't count your chickens
- before they're hatched?
- Clarence Litton's a billionaire.
Think he's gonna miss
a measly 500 grand?
Five hundred grand?
What are you, nuts?
The man's rich.
That's peanuts to him.
I can't talk to you
when you're like this.
- Like what?
- Delusional.
Stop that hat!
Oh, thanks.
Thanks.
Thought I was gonna
wind up swimming for it.
Then you would've had your hands
full because I'm a lousy swimmer.
You need to get one of those
strings that ties under your chin.
- Or a smaller hat.
- Or a bigger head.
You always dress like this
when you come to the beach?
Yeah, you never know
who you're gonna meet.
I'm Jerri Stone.
Cliff Lewis.
- So do you live around here?
- No, Atlanta, actually.
I'm just here helping
my father sell a house.
It's down there.
- On the beach?
- Yeah.
I've always wanted a
house on the beach.
Oh, you wouldn't want that
one. It's got a lot of problems.
How much is he asking for it?
Well, if my father was a
normal person, he'd ask 375.
That way, you know, he
could pay off the mortgage
and have a little
leftover to put in the bank.
But since my father is my
father, he wants way too much.
- Way too much?
- Way too much.
So, what do you do?
I'm a nurse.
In fact, my shift
starts in an hour.
I'm gonna have to go.
- Thanks for saving my hat.
- You're welcome.
- Nice meeting you.
Is that Jerri with a J or a G?
J.
I thought maybe, you know, I
might give you a call sometime.
That'd be nice.
I have to stay in
town indefinitely
just because some
deputy DA has trouble
with some gangster's phone bill?
That's crazy.
Well, Peter Haskins
hasn't had a chance
to prosecute somebody
famous before,
so I guess he figures the
bigger he makes the case,
the bigger office he'll get.
I have to get back to
Atlanta. I'm on a deadline.
You've been saying that as
far back as I can remember.
Well, it goes
with the territory.
I thought it'd change when
you married your editor.
Well, it didn't.
Well, do you see
Brad at all anymore?
No.
He's pretty busy now
that he's editor in chief.
I have seen Carrie, though,
right here in Wilmington.
She and Brad are spending
the summer at our...
His beach house in Castle Cove.
You should drop
by and say hello.
Maybe I will.
Hello?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay, I see.
I understand.
Thanks for the call.
That was Mr. Haskins.
He's found another
inconsistency in your story.
Now what?
Well, how did you say you got
into Adam Easley's room that night?
I've already told them that. I
knocked on the door and he let me in.
Well, the police have found somebody
who says that's not quite the case.
- Who?
- Ten-year-old boy,
staying across the hall.
He said he saw you
enter Adam Easley's room.
But you didn't knock.
Walked right in, and there
was no sign of Mr. Easley.
Well, he's wrong.
I mean, come on,
a 10-year-old kid?
He was probably so thrilled
to be talking to real-live cops
that he'd say anything
they wanted to hear.
It happens all the time, Ben.
Well, all I can tell you is
Mr. Haskins believes him,
and he thinks you're a liar.
You lied about
Mr. Easley and Mr. Baron,
the telephone
call, and now this.
I didn't lie, Ben.
He thinks you did.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Lewis.
- It's a pleasure to meet you.
- Feeling's mutual.
This here is my
son, the lawyer, Cliff.
- Yes, of course. How are you?
- Very fine, thank you.
Well, please, have a seat.
I take it Evelyn offered
you something to drink.
Yeah, but I told her no.
Told her we were
here to talk business,
not to have a tea party.
Well, I like your
attitude, Mr. Lewis.
I also like your house.
So do I. Got a lot
of sentimental value.
Used to belong to
my dear sister Lucy.
She owned that house
for less than six months
before she passed away.
But those were the happiest
six months of her life.
She loved that house.
The idea of somebody tearing it
down just to build something else
like, say, a big fancy hotel...
It would've broken her heart.
Oh, I don't know.
I'll bet that if I had made her the
offer that I'm about to make you,
she would've gotten
used to the idea in no time.
Here's what I'm prepared to
give you for that house, Mr. Lewis.
Five hundred and
five thousand dollars?
Yep.
- I don't believe it.
- Oh, no.
This is the part
you won't believe.
I turned them down.
You turned them down?
Come on, that's just
their first offer, Ben.
They're bound to go higher.
Even a country bumpkin
like you ought to know that.
To be honest with
you, I wasn't totally sure
I could make that
murder one charge stick,
even with the kid's testimony.
But now that I've read
that Forensics report,
there's not a doubt in my mind.
Well, I don't see anything
so earth-shattering here.
According to your client,
Adam Easley hit her on
the head with the phone.
- Right.
- Well, according to that report,
only the fingerprints of
Adam Easley's right hand
were found on the receiver.
Thing about it is Adam
Easley was left-handed.
Oh, come on. They
were struggling.
Maybe he had to hold
her arm with his left hand
and pick up the phone with
his right. He just had two.
Maybe. But then there's the
matter of Miss Barrett's fingerprints.
- What about them?
- If you'll turn to the next page,
you'll see they were found on
virtually every object in that motel room.
Which just does not
square with her contention
she was there for a very brief
period of time before killing Mr. Easley.
There was a commotion.
He was throwing her
from one side of
the room to the other.
Of course her fingerprints
were all over the place.
Your client is
lying, Mr. Matlock.
And the clincher is right
there on the next page.
What next page?
It's actually something the
investigating officer picked up
on the night of the murder.
Sure would like to be a fly on the wall
when Miss Barrett tries to explain that.
I scratched him
during the fight.
He grabbed me, and
he started slapping me,
and I remember raking
my fingers down his face.
And then I made a run for
the door when he let me go.
Mr. Haskins just showed me
a police report that indicates
the scratch marks went up
Adam Easley's face, not down.
- What?
- His skin was curled up
near his cheek,
not down by his jaw.
Somebody went like
that instead of like that:
I just remember clawing at him.
I guess my fingers could
have gone up instead of down.
Ellen, the man was a good
6, 8 inches taller than you.
It'd be next to impossible.
I don't care. That's
what happened.
The police think that
you scratched his face
after he was dead.
Now, why would I wanna do that?
To claim self-defense
instead of murder.
I didn't even know Adam Easley.
Why would I wanna kill him?
I don't know.
Mr. Haskins
wants to talk to you.
Talk to me or arrest me?
I'll go with you.
Might as well get it over with.
Mm.
Good choice.
I cannot believe that I
bumped into you again.
You look really nice.
Thank you. So do you.
Thank you.
So, uh, how's the
nursing business?
Well, I'm on a floor with 47
patients and two nurses, so it's busy.
- Yeah.
- What have you been up to?
Oh, arguing with my pop mostly.
Did he sell the house yet?
Oh, remember how I told you that
he wanted too much money for it?
- Yeah.
- Well, they offered him $505,000.
You're kidding.
- And he turned them down.
- You're kidding.
No, he figured that if the buyer
wanted the house bad enough
to offer him that much money,
he was bound to offer more.
Well, how high does
he think the guy will go?
Oh, he didn't say.
My dad is, um...
Well, I can't imagine that
they'd go much more than 6.
So if they make another
offer and it's anywhere near 6,
I'm gonna lock him in
the room until he takes it.
I don't blame you.
That's a lot of money.
- It's a lot of money.
- Yeah.
I'm really glad you
didn't have to work today.
Me too.
Oh, yuck.
- Oh, does that stain?
- Oh, yeah.
I'd better go home and
see if I can get this out.
Oh, well, do you
want me to drive you?
No, that's okay. My
car's right out in front.
Well, it's not a problem.
I don't mind driving.
We'll have to do this
some other time. I'm sorry.
I'll see you later.
Pardon me.
Hi.
Hi. What are you doing here?
Eating.
You're spying on me.
Well, yeah.
- What happened?
- Oh, she spilled wine on her skirt.
Is she coming back?
Probably not.
Well, you'll see her again.
Why do you say that?
I don't know.
Maybe I'm a mind
reader. Just a feeling.
Don't look so sad.
Of course there
are no hard feelings.
I'm a businessman
too, don't forget.
Yes, Mr. Lewis, I'll make sure
they validate your parking this time.
Good.
Well, I'll see you and your
son here tomorrow at 3.
Okay, bye.
You sure about this?
You offer them
anything over $600,000,
and I guarantee you
Cliff will cram it down
his father's throat.
You better be right.
It's bad enough I
have to deal with hicks,
but when they start
one-upping me, I...
Well, I just don't
like it, Miss Stone.
I just don't like that at all.
All of them said that they
were gonna pull their ads?
- Unless we what?
- Dad?
No, no, no, there's no way
in hell that I'm gonna do that.
Forget about it.
Yes, I realize that, but...
Listen, uh, let
me think about it
and I'll call you tomorrow,
okay? Okay, bye.
- Hi.
- Frank. Ingrid. How are you doing?
We're doing a lot better
than you are, I think.
Oh, well, some of our
advertisers are taking issue
with the pro-union editorials
I've been running, so...
I didn't just hear the
U word, did I, Ingrid?
Cover your ears, darling.
Frank contends that if
his mills ever went union,
he'd be out of
business within a week.
That's not so bad,
Frank. Think about it.
All the water skiing
you could get done.
Hey, you ought to see my new
boat. You saw it, didn't you, Carrie?
- Oh, yeah, it's beautiful.
- Come on over, go for a spin.
I'm taking her to the lake
tomorrow. It'll be your last chance.
Yes, come over.
I'll put on some steaks and
we'll all four have a barbecue.
Except I don't have
anything to make salad with.
Or any bread. And
we're all out of chips.
Be a dear and go raid
the refrigerator, would you?
Sure.
Kids like her almost, almost
make me wanna have one.
How are things between
Carrie and Ellen?
Oh, well, it's difficult.
Do you suppose there's something
Frank and I can do for Ellen?
Well, I don't think so.
Especially now.
What do you mean?
They just announced on the news.
She's been arrested.
For murder.
Well, you're quite right
about one thing, Mr. Lewis.
I wanna buy your house
because I wanna tear it
down and build a hotel there.
But if you're assuming that I'll
pay any amount of money to do so,
you're quite wrong.
Because I operate on a
budget like everyone else.
And this, therefore, must
be considered my final offer.
Six hundred and
twenty thousand dollars.
We'll take it.
Right, Pop?
Pop?
- Come on, son, let's go.
- Oh, hold on.
You just have to sign on the
line. Someone give him a pen.
- I'm not gonna sign that.
- He just offered you $620,000.
I heard him.
- Let's go.
- I'm not gonna let you do this now.
Why don't we just leave you
two alone so you can talk it over?
No need for talk.
I'm not taking less
than 800 and that's final.
Eight hundred?
- And I want the mortgage paid off too.
- What?
Not only does that
go beyond my budget,
it goes beyond common sense.
I'm afraid we have nothing more
to say to each other, Mr. Lewis.
These things happen.
Get out the parking ticket
so what's-her-name
out there can validate it.
- Seven hundred thousand.
- Seven seventy-five.
- Seven fifty.
- Plus 350 for the mortgage.
Plus 350 for the mortgage.
Now, you draw
that up and I'll sign it.
Sit down, son, before you fall.
One point one million dollars?
That's right, Ben. You're
looking at a millionaire.
Pop called his bluff,
the guy fell for it. I...
Any idea what yachts
go for these days?
Oh, what do you
care? You get seasick.
I'll just get me a gross of those little
patches you stick behind your ear,
and I'll be all set. Ha-ha-ha.
Wonder what Dora-Dora's
like this time of year.
That's Bora-Bora, Pop.
I'll get it.
- Hi.
- Hi, Jerri, what are you doing here?
- Can I talk to you?
- Yeah, yeah, come in. Sure.
Of course you can. Come on in.
Um, Ben, Dad,
this is Jerri Stone.
Jerri Stone, this is Ben Matlock
and my father, Billy Lewis.
I know who you are, Mr. Lewis.
That's why I'm here.
I'm not a nurse.
I'm a private investigator.
Clarence Litton
wanted me to find out
how much you expected
to get for this house.
Everything I did was on purpose.
Running into you on the beach
and then finding out how things
stood at the restaurant last night.
You told?
It's okay.
You're an unusual
man, Mr. Lewis.
All of the information that I gave to
Mr. Litton turned out to be useless.
Well, that's why he canned me.
But you know what? I don't
mind because you're nice people.
I started feeling bad
about the whole thing,
and I just wanted to apologize.
Especially to you.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
I've had to do some
underhanded things myself for Ben.
I've never asked you to
do anything underhanded.
- Sneaky?
- Sneaky, maybe,
but not underhanded.
Sneaky.
Well, I gotta go.
Hey, congratulations on
sticking it to old Litton like that.
He thought you
were just a dumb hick.
I know.
- Bye.
Classy lady.
Got guts too.
Too bad she can't hold a job.
Bail is at set $250,000.
As for the trial,
it will commence the
third of next month
at 9 a.m. in this courtroom.
Court is adjourned till 2:00.
This is weird.
I've been a spectator in court a
hundred times, but sitting here...
There were a couple dozen
reporters outside when I came in.
You might wanna go
down the back stairs.
- I know that's what I'm gonna do.
- Thanks.
Figure why make their jobs,
such as they are, any easier.
I hate reporters.
Ellen. Yoo-hoo!
- Ingrid.
- Oh, how are you, dear?
We have been so
worried about you.
- Hello, Ellen.
- Frank, hi.
Ben Matlock, these
are my friends,
- Frank and Ingrid Jefferies.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Nice to meet you.
Are you gonna be able to
raise all that bail money?
- Because...
- Oh, I can handle it. Thank you.
- Thanks for offering.
- Real reason why we came here
is because we heard you're
staying in some dreadful hotel.
Oh, well, I've been in worse.
Well, we think you
should stay with us.
You'd be near Carrie, and
she's very worried about you.
- Oh, it's tempting.
- We've got an extra bedroom.
- It seems a shame to waste it.
- Actually, it's his idea.
- Then I accept.
- Great.
- What's making all that racket?
- I don't know.
Couldn't decide
between red and white
so I got black.
Wanna go for a ride?
- Where did you...?
- From the bank.
Sold a house. Collateral.
They couldn't loan me
the money fast enough.
Pop, deals on houses
fall through every day.
Oh, take that
apron off and get in.
What's he got you doing
now? Baking cookies?
- No, we're making a stew.
- Billy.
Jealous, huh?
No, I'm not jealous.
You liked it when I had to
come crawling to you all the time
- to borrow money, didn't you?
- Are you crazy?
Ah! The worm has turned,
and you can't stand it.
I'm just afraid the worm's
gonna do something stupid.
I'm looking over a
four-leafed clover
That I overlooked before
Think it's hereditary?
Come on.
Be careful. Stand back.
- Come on, get the hose.
- I told you to get the hose.
Hey!
Mm. Mm.
Give me one all the way.
Wise choice, Mr. Matlock.
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
- Mind if I join you?
- Well, sure.
Uh, give me two,
please, with the works.
And a bag of chips...
- Two?
- And a root beer.
- So got a couple minutes to talk?
- Sure.
- I was wondering...
- Oh, Mr. Matlock.
I was just about to call you.
- Excuse us for a moment?
- Sure.
I've been talking to the police
up in Wallace all morning long.
Someone tried to burn
Adam Easley's house down.
- What?
- Last night, about midnight.
Definitely arson, definitely
not a professional job.
Made me think that maybe someone
who didn't have a lot of experience
was trying to destroy
something inside the house.
You talking about Ellen Barrett?
Yes.
So I had the police
search the house,
and they found
something very curious.
A book, written in Chinese,
published in Shanghai
about 20 years ago
titled Birth of a Criminal.
Wasn't exactly a
bestseller even then.
Almost impossible to get.
And yet that's the only book
they found in that whole house.
So I had somebody down at the
library do a quick translation, and bingo.
Oh, sure. Keep right on going.
What do you care, jerk?
- Where was I?
- Bingo.
Oh, yeah.
- Okay. Okay?
- Yeah, I guess so.
The book chronicles the
life of a real-life serial killer
from his childhood
right up to the execution.
It sounded suspiciously
similar in theme
to that series of articles your
client did for the Atlanta Herald
that won her the Pulitzer Prize.
So I compared the two.
They're the same, Mr. Matlock.
I finally have what
I've been looking for.
Motive.
Mr. Matlock.
You forgot your hot dog.
- What?
- I said where were you
between 11 and 1 last night?
I was right here, sleeping.
- Where were you?
- We were sleeping too.
- In another room.
- Of course.
So you can't say for
sure where Ellen was.
Ben, what's this about?
Our friend Mr. Haskins
knows about the book.
The police in Wallace retrieved
it from Adam Easley's house
after you tried to
burn it down last night.
I didn't burn down
anybody's house.
Ellen, the district
attorney has motive.
He's gonna contend that
you killed Adam Easley
because he was blackmailing you.
Because he knew
the Pulitzer Prize-winning
articles of yours were all plagiarized.
Plagiarized?
Ben, please, could we
do this somewhere else?
What's the difference?
By the end of the trial...
By the end of the day,
everybody's gonna know.
It's over, Ellen. So
how about the truth?
The DA's right about the book.
But he's wrong about me.
I didn't kill Adam Easley,
not in self-defense
or otherwise.
He was already dead
when I got to his room.
Well, why did you
say you killed him?
I can't tell you that.
How am I gonna defend you?
Oh, Ben, come on.
Clients lie to their lawyers
all the time. You know that.
Besides, I'm not lying. I
just can't tell you everything.
Oh, Ben, come on, please.
If you drop me, nobody
else is gonna touch me.
I'll be convicted for sure.
Ben, I didn't kill him.
Well, nothing on the news.
I guess the DA hasn't told
the press about the book.
You know what I feel like doing?
Remember when you and Brad
used to come over and we'd play bridge
out there, till dawn?
- Ingrid, they're divorced.
- I know.
But this morning in the store
when Frank was off skiing,
I started talking to this really
nice, very nice-looking man
about your age, and he
mentioned he plays bridge.
So why don't I go call him?
Now is not the time
to be fixing her up.
Why not? Romance strikes
when you least expect it.
She has other
things on her mind.
And I'm trying to get
her mind off those things.
I know you are, Ingrid. But I
kind of feel like being alone.
I just think I'll take a
long walk on the beach.
- Want some company?
- No, thanks.
Don't wait up for me.
- Oh, Ingrid.
- What was wrong with that?
Hello, Ellen.
What you got there?
Who the hell are you?
- I'll explain to you in the car.
- I'm not going anywhere with you.
Well, you know,
you got two choices.
Either you can come with
me or we can call the cops.
You decide.
- Well, who's that?
- Probably somebody
bringing your daddy
home in a straightjacket.
- Hi.
Mrs. Barrett would
like to talk to you.
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
- Bye.
- Okay, yeah.
- What's that?
- It's blood.
Let's sit down. This is
gonna be a long story.
Oh.
After, uh, I wound
up winning the Pulitzer
for those plagiarized
articles 15 years ago,
my conscience
started bothering me,
and eventually I told
Brad what I'd done.
You were still married then?
Yeah, and he was my editor.
I never told anybody else, but
somehow someone found out,
and a couple of weeks
ago, a man called Brad up
and he said that he would
make what I had done public
unless he was given $100,000.
He said his name
was Adam Easley.
I wonder why he put the
squeeze on Brad instead of you.
Oh, maybe he thought
he had more money
or more to lose or maybe both.
I don't know.
Anyway, Brad told me about the threat,
and he said that he'd take care of it.
But knowing that Brad doesn't
have the stomach for such things,
I got worried, and I...
At the last minute I
thought that I would go
and meet with this Easley too.
I went to his room
and I knocked.
When no one
answered, I tried the door.
It was unlocked.
I opened it, walked in,
and there was Easley,
lying dead on the floor.
The knife was next to him,
and the briefcase
was underneath him.
It was Brad's.
I figured that Brad had
gone there, met with Easley,
got mad, lost it,
and killed him.
I knew that if Brad
were arrested,
the plagiarism would come
out and we'd be ruined.
Brad, me, Carrie, all of us.
I see.
So I decided to make
it look like I'd killed him.
I went outside and I
buried the briefcase.
It was empty.
But I didn't want anything
of Brad's to be found.
Then I went back to the room.
I guess that's when
the boy saw me.
- No, I'm not gonna go!
- And I called the police.
And then while you were
waiting for them to come,
you staged the scene.
I tore my blouse,
then I wiped the knife clean,
and I put my fingerprints on it.
I knocked over some furniture,
scratched his face.
And I whacked
myself with the phone.
And when the police
came, you told them that lie
about Adam Easley
working for Vic Baron.
- Yes.
- Well, why'd you dig up the briefcase?
So I could get rid of it.
Brad did it.
I think that's a
safe assumption.
You haven't talked to him?
We agreed not to contact each
other until after he'd talked to Easley.
We wanted to make sure
that Carrie never found out.
You know, that's the first
time we agreed on anything
in almost 14 years.
Well, to tell you the truth,
after I overheard what the deputy
DA told you in the courthouse,
I thought maybe I'd do a little
freelancing and follow Ellen.
I figured if I came up with
something, maybe you'd hire me.
That's why you came
to the courthouse?
Yeah.
I know you have Cliff,
but he doesn't strike
me as the kind of person
who's particularly good at...
- Sneaking around?
- Yes.
Well, he's, uh...
The truth is I don't have
anything for you right now.
This case, every time I
think I got a handle on it,
you know, pull the old
rabbit out of the hat?
I look in there and
there ain't no rabbit.
Well, maybe I could do
some more freelancing.
No, no. I don't like that.
I don't want people
going behind my back.
Especially people
who work for me.
So Ellen thinks
that I killed him?
You did, didn't you?
No, no.
Well, she found your
briefcase under the body.
I was there that night,
but I did not kill him.
He was alive when I left.
Let's hear it.
All right. Okay.
This guy, Easley, called
me a couple of weeks ago
and said that he knew
Ellen had gotten the Pulitzer
by plagiarizing that book.
Said if I didn't pay
him 100 grand, he'd tell.
So I got him the cash and
I met him in his room at 9.
Is that the money?
Wait a minute. I
don't want some copy.
I want the book.
The book's my insurance policy.
How do I know you're
not gonna do this again?
Guess you'll just
have to trust me.
And that was it. I
went straight home.
After Carrie went
to bed that evening,
I threw the copy that he had given
me into the fireplace and I burned it.
Well, the police estimate the
time of death to be about 9:30.
Well, I was home
long before then.
Who did you think had done it?
Ellen. I figured she had gone
over there for some reason
and got into a fight with the
guy and killed him in self-defense,
- just like she said.
- What'd you think happened
- to your briefcase and the money?
- I figured Ellen took it.
First she said she did it, and
then she said she didn't do it,
said you did it.
And then you said you
didn't do it, said she did it.
I wish you'd get
your stories straight.
Oh, no.
Carrie...
Mom got that prize by cheating?
And you knew about it.
All those years
you've been living a lie.
Is that why you divorced?
Because of the lie?
You've lectured
me about honesty.
Your honesty cost me a mother.
- And a father.
- Carrie. Carrie.
Carrie.
Ellen.
Figured I might find you here.
- Ben Matlock came to see me today.
- I know, he told me.
Unfortunately, Carrie was listening,
and she overheard everything.
- What do you mean everything?
- Everything.
Oh, for crying out loud, Brad,
how could you let that happen?
All right, I'm sorry.
She was very upset. She
ran out of the house in tears.
- She ran away?
- Yeah.
She got back an hour
ago. She's up there now.
I've sat her down and
explained everything to her,
and she's handling it.
Just sitting there listening to music,
or at least what she calls music.
Did you tell her that
stealing from that book,
- I've regretted every day of my life?
- The best I could.
I love her, Brad.
The last thing in the world I want
is for her to be hurt by my stupidity.
That's why I covered for you when I
thought that you killed Adam Easley.
Ellen, I didn't
kill Adam Easley.
Well, what was I supposed to think?
He was lying on top of your briefcase.
I figured you'd killed him.
And I knew watching you go to
prison would break Carrie's heart.
I couldn't let that happen.
They almost ready?
Few seconds.
Of course he said Adam
Easley was alive when he left.
What else was he gonna say?
He had to know that
incriminates Ellen.
Well, maybe he didn't care.
How did this Adam Easley
guy wind up with the book
that she plagiarized?
People familiar with
obscure Chinese literature
generally aren't blackmailers.
Somebody gave it to him.
Maybe that's who killed him.
Yeah. Hey, maybe
they were partners.
You know, uh, instead of settling
for half the blackmail money,
they could have wanted the
whole thing so they killed him.
You know, there's
still 100 grand missing.
Okay, here you go.
- Blueberry pancakes.
- Oh, yes.
- Good.
I think we should go for
this Adam Easley guy.
Well, the police say that he
owed two months back rent
on the house in Wallace, and he
had no visible means of support.
Hadn't filed an income
tax return in five years,
and, at this point, no one's
come forward to claim his body.
It's hard to know
where to begin.
How about with him?
People who can eat
from morning to night
without getting
fat drive me crazy.
Thanks a lot.
So this is the
infamous Adam Easley.
Medical examiner did a
real number on him, huh?
Looks like he put everything
back pretty much in the right place.
- You okay?
- Mm.
Haven't you ever
done this before?
Oh, you should've
said something.
I used to do this all the
time when I was a cop.
I always thought it was so cool
how you could learn so much
from people just by
looking at their corpses.
For instance,
look at that liver.
See how kind of puffy it is?
Beginning stages of cirrhosis.
This guy liked to drink.
Sure was tan.
Take a look at this.
Calluses all across
his palm. See that?
Hmm.
Left hand too.
Look at that. Tan
line on his ring finger.
Was he wearing a ring
when they bagged him?
Watch, wallet, gold
necklace. No rings.
Huh.
Well, if it was a wedding band,
looks like he was wearing
it till pretty recently.
Maybe there's an
ex-wife somewhere.
Maybe she's the one
with all the answers.
Mom!
Oh, Carrie.
How could you do it?
How many countless times
I've asked myself that question.
I was young, I was ambitious,
and incredibly stupid.
And you thought no
one would ever find out?
Well, I thought that
I could live with it.
And in time, I thought I had to.
I hope you can forgive
me someday, Carrie.
I was dishonest, I
lied, I cheated, I stole,
and I lived with it.
And I made your
dad live with it.
That's what ruined our marriage.
I lost him and I lost you.
You didn't lose me.
You just didn't want me.
Oh, Carrie, no.
I didn't fight for custody of you
because I thought I didn't deserve you.
Mr. Haskins.
Mr. Haskins!
Ideally,
what you hear in a
court of law is the truth.
But I'm afraid that what
you're gonna hear mostly
in this court of law are lies.
You will hear how Ellen
Barrett told the police
that she went to Adam
Easley's hotel room
to get information on
a suspected mobster
named Vic Baron.
You will hear how Adam Easley
greeted her at the door as a friend
and how chagrinned she was
when moments later he told
her he'd been sent by Vic Baron
to beat her up.
You will hear how she...
How he.
Pulled her hair
and he tore her clothes
and he hit her on the head,
and how she, in turn,
scratched his face
and ultimately stabbed him
to death with a steak knife.
But these will
have all been lies.
Because you will then
hear how no connection
between Adam Easley and
Vic Baron has ever been found,
how in all likelihood,
the injuries she suffered
were self-inflicted,
and how the scratch
mark on the victim
was put there after he was dead.
You will hear how Miss
Barrett tried to make it look
as if she murdered Adam
Easley in self-defense,
when in point of fact, it
was premeditated murder.
Why did she kill him?
Ladies and gentlemen,
couched in that answer
is the biggest lie of all.
Because you will
hear how Ellen Barrett,
famous reporter and columnist,
renowned for the series of
articles she wrote years ago
that won her the Pulitzer Prize,
how she was being
blackmailed by Adam Easley.
Why?
Because he found out
that that series of articles
had, in fact, been
written by somebody else.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Adam Easley is dead
because he found out that
Ellen Barrett is a plagiarist.
- Found him.
- Ah.
Are you sure I can't
get you anything?
Oh, no, I'm fine. Thank you.
- Is this you in all these pictures?
- Yep.
Frank skis
practically every day.
Even when he's making
the rounds of his mills,
he comes home by
way of Lake George.
But I don't mind. I like
what it does for his pecs.
- Ingrid.
- Ha, ha, ha.
What can we do for you?
Well, I'm just still trying to
get a handle on this case.
Think...
Did you happen to
be home that night?
I wasn't.
Tuesday is ladies'
night at the racquet club.
I was home.
Uh, you remember
if Brad was home?
Is that what you're doing?
You're checking up on Brad.
Well, you're a friend of his,
and he lives across the street.
And like they say, the
truth never hurts, so I just...
Well, I know he was home at 11
because there was something
about Ellen on the news,
and I called him
right away to tell him.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
You remember
seeing him before that?
Yes, as a matter of fact, I do.
I saw him pull into the driveway. I
remember because his headlights
shine right into our house
whenever he pulls in.
Just between you, me and the
lamppost, it's really annoying.
Uh... When would that have been?
Well, seems to me I was
watching Inside the FBI at the time.
- He never misses that show.
- So it must have been sometime
between 9 and 9:30.
Well, I had a feeling
Brad didn't do it.
Well, who do you think did?
Oh, well, uh, I'm
damned if I know.
There's a dog in here.
Mrs. Easley!
Are you in there?
Hello?
You shouldn't torment the dog.
Hey, if she's in there, she's gonna
come out and see what's going on.
Hush up.
I told them yesterday I wasn't
gonna have any money till Friday.
No, whoa, whoa, we
don't want any money.
We just wanna talk to
you about your ex-husband.
Bum's dead. What's to ask?
When was the last
time you saw him?
About a week before he died.
Was that here or up in Wallace?
Lake George.
He just about lived out there.
Kept the place in Wallace
just so he could take a shower
once in a while.
I went up there to tell him
that the divorce was final
and that he owed me
four months' child support.
Told him I'd gotten a lawyer
and was gonna go
after his lousy ski boat
if he didn't pay up.
A water ski boat?
That's why we
never had any money.
It all went into
hanging around the lake
trying to impress those
rich dudes out there.
Parties, beer, wine, whiskey.
That damn ski
boat, the Candy Man.
Anyway, Adam said he'd have
the money for me in a week.
Then the bum goes and dies,
and here I am hiding in the bathroom
every time there's a knock on the door
for fear that it's
a bill collector.
Did he say where he
was gonna get the money?
He didn't say.
I didn't ask.
Adam wasn't a man what you'd
call had a whole lot of principles.
Oh, hello. I'm Clarence Litton.
Is Mr. Lewis here?
- Oh, yes, come on in, please.
- Thank you.
Here.
- Billy?
- What?
Billy?
What?
Hello, Mr. Lewis.
I stopped by because
I'm afraid there's...
Well, there's a small problem,
and I'd like to explain
it to you personally.
You're not gonna buy the house?
Yes, we're going
to buy the house.
But, unfortunately, we're
not gonna be able to do so
- as soon as we'd planned.
- What do you mean?
Oh, due to some mix-up
in our Legal Department,
we're not gonna be able to pay
off the mortgage until Thursday,
not tomorrow as we agreed.
- Thursday? This Thursday?
- Correct, correct.
But in the meantime,
I brought by a check
for what we agreed to pay you,
well, in hopes that it would help
you accept our profound apologies
for the slight delay.
Yeah, okay.
Of course I'll have to
run this Thursday thing
by my son the lawyer,
see what he says.
Oh, of course, of course.
And if he has any
questions, Mr. Lewis,
just have him call me
and we'll discuss this...
- Always a pleasure.
- Good.
- Thank you, Mr. Lewis. Goodbye.
Let me see that.
Seven hundred and
fifty thousand smackers.
I'll just parlay that
into a couple of million.
Now, water skiing, that could
explain Adam Easley's dark tan.
- And the calluses on his hands.
- Yeah.
You know, I think this
is gonna work out good.
- What?
- Well, you and me
teaming up like this.
You wanna have
some dinner tonight?
Oh, Cliff, I don't think...
You don't think I'm your type,
right? I... That's all right, I understand.
Well, it's just that I recently
broke up with somebody
and I'm not really ready to get
involved with somebody else.
- You know what I mean?
- Yeah.
Good.
I think I saw a phone over by that
gas station. I'm gonna go call Ben.
I'll, uh, just meet
you by the boats.
Okay.
I'll see you over there then.
This ain't your boat, pal.
You the one that's been
- ripping everybody off down here?
- No. No.
You the one that got
my radio last week?
Come here.
This is not your boat.
I know that, I know that.
If you'll give me one
moment, I'll explain.
Help! Boat loose!
Somebody help me!
Oh.
- You got it?
- Yeah, I got it.
Oh, good.
Yeah, hold on. Bring it around.
Yeah.
- This yours?
- Yeah. Thanks, I owe you one.
- Don't mention it.
- No, really.
How about I buy you a drink?
Sure.
Yeah.
Mr. Matlock?
Hi.
I am Carrie Gelardi.
I was coming to see you.
Oh. The last time I saw you,
you were as big as a grasshopper.
It doesn't look very
good for my mom, does it?
Um...
- Well...
- I hope you're not gonna try
and pin it on my dad.
Well, to tell you the truth...
Because he was telling
the truth, Mr. Matlock.
He was home at 9:15. I
know because of my car.
- Your car?
- Yeah.
I parked my car in the driveway
and when I park my
car in the driveway,
he can't park his
car in the garage.
Oh. Well, did you move
your car so he could...?
No. No, he was too upset.
He was so upset he said forget
it and left his car in the street.
I'm really worried
about the both of them.
Well, I...
Well, thank you
for the information.
I'll see you later.
What say, Frank?
Mr. Matlock, what's up?
Remember you told me
how you saw Brad's headlights
when he turned
into his driveway?
- Yeah.
- I just found out
that he didn't turn into
his driveway that night.
So you couldn't have
seen his headlights.
You caught me.
Why'd you lie?
I've known Brad for 20 years.
He came to my wedding. I
saw him through his divorce.
There's no way in hell
he could kill anyone.
He's a good guy.
I was just trying to
protect him, that's all.
Maybe what I did was wrong,
but I did it for
the right reason.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
What were you doing
out at Lake George?
Oh, Adam Easley's ex-wife said
that he was out there water skiing
about a week before he died,
and that he was about to
come into a lot of money.
Uh, so we went out
there, we found his boat.
Had a little run-in with his dock mate
who's very strong and not very nice.
Oh, he was nice to me.
He bought me a drink.
Right.
Anyway, uh, we came
up empty-handed.
Did you say Adam Easley
water skis out at Lake George?
- All the time.
- Well, that's interesting
because Brad Gelardi's next
door neighbor, Frank Jefferies,
does too.
Hmm.
Can she bake a cherry
pie Billy Boy, Billy Boy?
pie Charming Billy?
She can bake a cherry pie
She's the apple of my eye
She's a young thing And
cannot leave her mother
Hey, I'm gonna have
to tune up the old guitar.
Yeah. I got some good news.
- What?
- Well, I went back out to the lake,
and I showed the picture of
Frank Jefferies to my new pal.
- Did he recognize him?
- Yep.
Didn't know who he
was, but he did say
that he'd seen him with
Adam Easley a couple of times.
- Oh, then we're on the right track.
- Mm-hm.
- How's it going here?
- Eh.
Wonder what happened
to all that money.
Here's a passbook.
Well, the last big deposit was
made two months before the murder.
That won't help us.
Come on now, come on.
Children, not on the carpet.
I just got them shampooed.
Pizza will be here any minute.
Pizza! Pizza!
Pizza!
Your maid let us
in, Miss Jefferies.
We have a warrant
to search the premises.
Back outside. Come on, let's go.
Let's go. Now, come on.
All of you, all of you.
- Right now, right now.
- Golly.
Or no pizza.
What are you doing here?
Well, just checking bank
statements and such.
Like I say, we have a warrant.
Are Frank and I suspects?
They're just
covering all the bases.
Who are the kids?
Underprivileged children.
I throw a beach party
for them every summer.
That's nice.
Well, we'll be going,
and have a nice party.
Pizza's here, Mrs. Jefferies.
- Excuse us.
- Sorry.
- I'm sorry, I can't break a hundred.
- You're kidding.
- Why not? What am I supposed...?
- I think maybe I can.
- Uh, let's see, let's see.
- Great.
Here's... Here's a 20
and a 20 and two 5's
and a, uh, 50.
Oh, Mr. Matlock,
you're a lifesaver.
Thank you.
Is this the briefcase you gave
to the decedent that night?
Yes, it is.
What was in it when
you gave it to him?
One hundred thousand
dollars in $100 bills.
What's in it now?
- Nothing.
- Your Honor, we already know
that's the briefcase that was found
underneath the decedent's body.
It's already entered
into evidence.
Mr. Matlock?
Why didn't you come forward
when Ellen was arrested?
I was ashamed.
Nothing further.
No questions.
He told me a lot of things when he
and Ellen were going through the divorce.
He needed someone
to confide in, and I was it.
Uh, how do you make
a living, Mr. Jefferies?
I own a half
dozen textile mills.
Been in my family for years.
- They union or nonunion?
- Nonunion.
Uh, what would happen
if they went union?
I'd have to shut them down.
I couldn't afford to run them.
I don't know.
I don't know, I think
you could afford it.
It's just that you and your
CEOs wouldn't be able to draw
such nice big
salaries, would you?
That's the real reason
you scream "shut down"
every time that five-letter word
that starts with a U comes up, isn't it?
I pay my workers well,
and I treat them fairly.
- And they'd be the first to say so.
- Well, that may be,
but there is a movement to
unionize mills like yours, isn't there?
Like in those editorials
in the Atlanta Herald?
- Are they pro- or anti-union?
- Pro.
They keep fanning the
flames, don't they? Heh, heh.
Does that bother you?
Of course it bothers me.
Who's editor in
chief of the Herald?
Brad Gelardi.
Well, he's a friend of yours.
Didn't you talk to him,
try to get him to stop
publishing that stuff pro-union?
- Of course I did, but...
- He kept fanning the flames.
He kept fanning the flames,
didn't he? Yeah, yeah.
Flames that, uh, could
ruin your business, maybe.
Certainly your lifestyle.
And so since arguing
with him wouldn't help,
you decided on
more drastic moves.
You figured out a way
to not only get him fired,
but to ruin his character
and discredit him and
everything he stood for,
- didn't you?
- Objection!
What in the world do
mills and unions have to do
with whether or not Ellen Barrett
committed first degree murder?
I just got started, Peter.
For heaven's sakes.
Mr. Matlock.
I'll tie it up, Your
Honor. I promise.
Proceed. Objection overruled.
I understand you like to
water ski, Mr. Jefferies.
Yes, I do.
The decedent, Adam
Easley, liked to water ski.
- Did you know that?
- No.
Oh, yeah. He had a ski boat down
at Lake George and everything.
You got a ski boat?
- Yes, I do.
- Oh.
He got a ski boat, you got a ski
boat. Where do you keep yours?
Lake George.
Did you know Adam Easley?
No.
Well, there's a man here
who docked his boat
next to Adam Easley's boat,
and he's prepared to testify
that he saw you and
Mr. Easley together
on numerous occasions.
- He's mistaken.
- Objection.
We got mills and unions
and water skiing and boats.
Just when does Mr. Matlock
plan to get around to something
that is relevant to this case?
Mr. Haskins, give me a break.
You did say something
about tying all this up,
didn't you, Mr. Matlock?
Yes, sir.
Were you aware that Ellen
Barrett plagiarized the articles
- that won her the Pulitzer Prize?
- No.
Well, that's odd.
I understood that your
friend, Brad Gelardi,
told you they were
plagiarized and that he knew it.
Um...
Yeah, actually I
think he did tell me.
Actually, he's
prepared to testify
that in the middle of his divorce
when you were his closest friend,
- he told you.
- I guess I forgot.
Yeah. And you decided
to take that knowledge
that he trusted you with
and use it to nip this
union business in the bud
by framing him for murder
and by exposing him as a
man who condoned plagiarism.
- At least, that was the plan, wasn't it?
- No.
And so you obtained a
copy of the Chinese book
that Ellen had plagiarized
and gave it to your water-skiing
buddy, Adam Easley,
and had him make the call to Brad
about the blackmail money, didn't you?
- No.
- You told him to ask
for $100,000 in cash.
Then you arranged for Mr. Easley
to meet Brad at that motel
and collect it.
Not one word of this is true.
After Brad left,
you showed up, wearing gloves.
And you did something
that Adam Easley didn't
expect at all, didn't you?
You picked up the steak knife
- and killed him!
- No!
He was holding the briefcase
and, good for you, he fell on it.
I didn't kill him.
I wasn't there.
You removed the
money from the briefcase,
put the case back under the
body so the police would assume
that Brad was the killer.
And then you left.
That's not true.
What you didn't know
is that Brad had told
Ellen about the blackmail,
and she was afraid that
somehow he might botch the payoff.
So after you left the
motel, she showed up,
saw the body,
and she assumed what you
wanted everybody else to assume,
that Brad had done it.
So to protect Brad and herself,
she staged that scene to
make it look like self-defense.
When all the time,
it was you, wasn't it?
- No. This is outrageous.
- Objection! Proof!
Proof! It is obvious to me
Mr. Matlock has absolutely
no concept of the word "proof."
Mr. Haskins, I've been an officer
of the court for my entire adult life.
Do you really think I'd
go this far without proof?
How about it?
All right, right here.
Right here in this little sack.
What has $100 bill
got to do with anything?
He said, "What's $100
bill got to do with anything?"
I was just getting to that.
Scout's honor, Your Honor.
Go ahead, fast.
Okay.
You know where I got
this $100 bill, Mr. Jefferies?
I have no idea.
Your wife gave it to me.
Detective Marks saw her
give it to me the other day
in exchange for
some smaller bills.
It occurred to me
that it might be
one of $100 bills
that Brad took to Adam
Easley the night of the murder.
And I hoped the lab
could find fingerprints.
What they found was even better.
Know what it was?
Again, I have no idea.
Traces of Adam Easley's blood.
It was part of the
missing blackmail money.
How'd your wife end up with it?
You gave it to her.
How did you end up with it?
It was part of the money you took
out of that blood-soaked briefcase
after you stabbed
Adam Easley to death.
Wasn't it, Mr. Jefferies?
No more questions.
We find the defendant,
Ellen Barrett, not guilty.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Bail is exonerated and
the defendant is free to go.
Mom.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Okay, I'm taking
both of you to lunch.
Now that you're both unemployed
and we have nothing better to do,
maybe we can finally learn
how to talk to one another.
Go to lunch?
After whipping
my tail like that?
Making a fool out of me?
Humiliating me in
front of my peers?
- I'm buying.
- I'm easy.
You think we'll
all fit in that car?
It'll be a tight squeeze.
No worse than the cheap
seats on most airplanes.
Lord knows you're used to them.
Oh, I don't know, Ben.
What?
Think I should have sold
Lucy's house like that?
It's a little late for
seller's remorse, Billy.
Yeah, but she was my sister.
She spent her last years here.
Now, thanks to me,
they're gonna tear it all
down and plow it under
like some big patch of weeds.
Maybe I shouldn't have sold it.
Maybe I should've
just let it sit.
- Kind of like the Lincoln Memorial.
- Yeah.
Billy, I think it's good for
you to feel guilty like this.
And I don't wish to
speak evil of the dead,
but I think you're
forgetting something here.
Lucy was nasty,
mean, ornery,
hateful, muleheaded.
And you had to live
with her for 40 years.
You gave up 40 years
of your life. Forty years.
You hated her, Billy.
Thanks, Ben.
I needed that.
www.tvsubtitles.net